{
	"description": "Quirky kanji with sneaky readings",
	"deck": [
	{ "question": "丁稚", "answers": [ "でっち" ], "comment": "apprentice; shop boy" },
	{ "question": "上梓", "answers": [ "じょうし" ], "comment": "publication; wood-block printing" },
	{ "question": "下賜", "answers": [ "かし" ], "comment": "grant; bestowal; giving something to someone of low social standing (by a person of very high social standing)" },
	{ "question": "不味い", "answers": [ "まずい" ], "comment": "unappetising; unappetizing; unsavoury; unsavory; unpleasant\nunskillful; unskilful; bungling; clumsy; poor\nugly; unattractive; homely; plain\nawkward; problematic; troublesome; unfavorable; unfavourable; unwise" },
	{ "question": "不如帰", "answers": [ "ほととぎす" ], "comment": "lesser cuckoo (Cuculus poliocephalus)" },
	{ "question": "不束", "answers": [ "ふつつか" ], "comment": "rude; inexperienced; stupid; incompetent" },
	{ "question": "不知火", "answers": [ "しらぬい" ], "comment": "phosphorescent light; mysterious lights on the sea; sea fire" },
	{ "question": "不躾", "answers": [ "ぶしつけ" ], "comment": "ill-bred; impolite; rude; impudent; insolent; blunt" },
	{ "question": "与する", "answers": [ "くみする" ], "comment": "to take part in; to be implicated in; to side with; to support" },
	{ "question": "且つ", "answers": [ "かつ" ], "comment": "yet; moreover; and" },
	{ "question": "世迷言", "answers": [ "よまいごと" ], "comment": "grumbling; muttering; nonsense" },
	{ "question": "乃至", "answers": [ "ないし" ], "comment": "from ... to; between ... and\nor" },
	{ "question": "久遠", "answers": [ "くおん" ], "comment": "eternity" },
	{ "question": "乖離", "answers": [ "かいり" ], "comment": "divergence; alienation; deviation; estrangement; separation; detachment" },
	{ "question": "予め", "answers": [ "あらかじめ" ], "comment": "beforehand; in advance; previously" },
	{ "question": "云々", "answers": [ "うんぬん" ], "comment": "and so on; and so forth; et cetera; and such; and the like\ncomment; criticism" },
	{ "question": "五月蠅い", "answers": [ "うるさい" ], "comment": "noisy; loud\nannoying; troublesome; tiresome; persistent; importunate\nfussy; finicky; picky; particular; nagging; fastidious; bossy\nshut up!; be quiet!" },
	{ "question": "五月雨", "answers": [ "さみだれ" ], "comment": "early-summer rain" },
	{ "question": "些か", "answers": [ "いささか" ], "comment": "a little; a bit; somewhat; slightly; rather" },
	{ "question": "些細", "answers": [ "ささい" ], "comment": "trivial; slight" },
	{ "question": "亡骸", "answers": [ "なきがら" ], "comment": "remains; corpse; (dead) body" },
	{ "question": "人熱れ", "answers": [ "ひといきれ" ], "comment": "body heat from several people in close quarters; stuffy air" },
	{ "question": "人集り", "answers": [ "ひとだかり" ], "comment": "crowd; throng" },
	{ "question": "介錯", "answers": [ "かいしゃく" ], "comment": "beheading (as the ending to a seppuku)\nassistance; help" },
	{ "question": "他所", "answers": [ "よそ" ], "comment": "another place; somewhere else; strange parts\noutside (one's family or group); those people\nunrelated matter\nanother place; somewhere else; elsewhere\nmoving (to another place)" },
	{ "question": "仙人掌", "answers": [ "さぼてん" ], "comment": "cactus" },
	{ "question": "仰る", "answers": [ "おっしゃる" ], "comment": "to say; to speak; to tell; to talk" },
	{ "question": "似非", "answers": [ "えせ" ], "comment": "false; would-be; sham; pretended; mock; spurious; pseudo; quasi" },
	{ "question": "何れ", "answers": [ "いずれ" ], "comment": "which (of three or more)\nwhichever; any\nwell; now; let me see\nwhere; which; who\nanyway; anyhow; at any rate\nsooner or later; eventually; one of these days; at some future date or time\nboth; either; any; all; whichever" },
	{ "question": "作務衣", "answers": [ "さむえ" ], "comment": "monk's working clothes; monk's non-spiritual clothes" },
	{ "question": "侠客", "answers": [ "きょうかく" ], "comment": "self-styled humanitarian; chivalrous person; persons acting under the pretence of chivalry who formed gangs and engaged in gambling" },
	{ "question": "俯く", "answers": [ "うつむく" ], "comment": "to hang one's head; to look down; to cast one's eyes downward" },
	{ "question": "倦む", "answers": [ "うむ" ], "comment": "to get tired of (doing); to lose interest in" },
	{ "question": "倶楽部", "answers": [ "くらぶ" ], "comment": "club; fraternity; sorority; clubhouse" },
	{ "question": "健気", "answers": [ "けなげ" ], "comment": "admirable; commendable; praiseworthy; laudable; brave; heroic; noble; courageous" },
	{ "question": "僥倖", "answers": [ "ぎょうこう" ], "comment": "fortuitous; luck; windfall; godsend; good fortune" },
	{ "question": "僻む", "answers": [ "ひがむ" ], "comment": "to have a warped view; to be jaundiced; to be prejudiced\nto feel that one has been unfairly treated\nto be jealous; to be envious; to have an inferiority complex" },
	{ "question": "億劫", "answers": [ "おっくう" ], "comment": "troublesome; annoying" },
	{ "question": "兎に角", "answers": [ "とにかく" ], "comment": "anyhow; at any rate; anyway; somehow or other; generally speaking; in any case; at least" },
	{ "question": "入内", "answers": [ "じゅだい" ], "comment": "imperial bridal party's entry into the court" },
	{ "question": "八百万", "answers": [ "やおよろず" ], "comment": "myriad; countless things\neight million" },
	{ "question": "公達", "answers": [ "きんだち" ], "comment": "kings; children of nobles; young nobleman\nofficial announcement" },
	{ "question": "冤罪", "answers": [ "えんざい" ], "comment": "false charge; false accusation; misrepresentation" },
	{ "question": "凋落", "answers": [ "ちょうらく" ], "comment": "decline; fall; decay; withering" },
	{ "question": "凛々しい", "answers": [ "りりしい" ], "comment": "gallant; brave; imposing; awe-inspiring; severe; biting; chivalrous; manly; dignified" },
	{ "question": "凡例", "answers": [ "はんれい" ], "comment": "explanatory notes (at the start of a book); introductory remarks; usage guide (e.g. of a dictionary)\nlegend (on maps, drawings, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "凱旋", "answers": [ "がいせん" ], "comment": "triumphal return" },
	{ "question": "出奔", "answers": [ "しゅっぽん" ], "comment": "flight; elopement; running away; absconding" },
	{ "question": "刮げる", "answers": [ "こそげる" ], "comment": "to scrape off; to shave off" },
	{ "question": "刮目", "answers": [ "かつもく" ], "comment": "careful observation; close attention" },
	{ "question": "刹那", "answers": [ "せつな" ], "comment": "moment; instant; juncture" },
	{ "question": "刺青", "answers": [ "いれずみ" ], "comment": "tattoo" },
	{ "question": "剣呑", "answers": [ "けんのん" ], "comment": "risky; dangerous; insecure" },
	{ "question": "割烹", "answers": [ "かっぽう" ], "comment": "cooking (esp. Japanese style); cuisine" },
	{ "question": "労る", "answers": [ "いたわる" ], "comment": "to pity; to sympathize with; to sympathise with; to treat with sympathy; to console; to be kind to; to appreciate\nto tend to (e.g. an injury); to care for; to nurse; to soothe" },
	{ "question": "勤しむ", "answers": [ "いそしむ" ], "comment": "to endeavor; to endeavour; to work hard (at)" },
	{ "question": "匍匐", "answers": [ "ほふく" ], "comment": "creeping; crawling; sneaking" },
	{ "question": "匿う", "answers": [ "かくまう" ], "comment": "to shelter; to shield; to hide" },
	{ "question": "十姉妹", "answers": [ "じゅうしまつ" ], "comment": "Bengalese finch; society finch (Lonchura striata var. domestica)" },
	{ "question": "南瓜", "answers": [ "かぼちゃ" ], "comment": "pumpkin (Cucurbita sp.); squash" },
	{ "question": "博打", "answers": [ "ばくち" ], "comment": "gambling" },
	{ "question": "却って", "answers": [ "かえって" ], "comment": "on the contrary; rather; all the more; instead" },
	{ "question": "厭う", "answers": [ "いとう" ], "comment": "to be loath to; to balk at (doing); to grudge (doing); to spare (oneself); to be weary of; to shun; to dislike (an activity, an environment); to hate (an activity)\nto take (good) care of" },
	{ "question": "厳か", "answers": [ "おごそか" ], "comment": "solemn (ceremony, atmosphere, etc.); austere; grave; majestic; dignified; stately; impressive" },
	{ "question": "反吐", "answers": [ "へど" ], "comment": "spew; vomiting" },
	{ "question": "反故", "answers": [ "ほご" ], "comment": "wastepaper; scrap paper" },
	{ "question": "収斂", "answers": [ "しゅうれん" ], "comment": "astringency\nextraction (of taxes)\nconvergence; contraction" },
	{ "question": "口伝", "answers": [ "くでん" ], "comment": "oral instruction\npassing information by word-of-mouth\noral tradition" },
	{ "question": "口説く", "answers": [ "くどく" ], "comment": "to persuade; to coax; to solicit\nto seduce; to make advances; to make a play; to make a pass; to put the moves on; to come on to; to hit on; to court; to woo; to romance" },
	{ "question": "叩頭", "answers": [ "こうとう" ], "comment": "kowtow (bow made from a kneeling position wherein the forehead touches the ground)" },
	{ "question": "台詞", "answers": [ "せりふ" ], "comment": "speech; words; one's lines; remarks" },
	{ "question": "叱咤", "answers": [ "しった" ], "comment": "scolding; rebuke; reprimand\nfierce encouragement; exhorting" },
	{ "question": "向日葵", "answers": [ "ひまわり" ], "comment": "sunflower (Helianthus annuus)" },
	{ "question": "吝か", "answers": [ "やぶさか" ], "comment": "reluctant; hesitant" },
	{ "question": "吹聴", "answers": [ "ふいちょう" ], "comment": "spreading around (news, rumor, etc.); making widely known; making public; publicizing; proclaiming" },
	{ "question": "呂律", "answers": [ "ろれつ" ], "comment": "articulation" },
	{ "question": "呆気ない", "answers": [ "あっけない" ], "comment": "unsatisfying; disappointing; abrupt; not enough; too quick; too short; over too soon" },
	{ "question": "呑気", "answers": [ "のんき" ], "comment": "carefree; optimistic; careless; reckless; heedless; happy-go-lucky; easygoing; thoughtless" },
	{ "question": "呪詛", "answers": [ "じゅそ" ], "comment": "curse; malediction; hex" },
	{ "question": "呵責", "answers": [ "かしゃく" ], "comment": "blame; accusation; torture; maltreatment; pangs (of conscience)" },
	{ "question": "呻く", "answers": [ "うめく" ], "comment": "to moan; to groan" },
	{ "question": "咀嚼", "answers": [ "そしゃく" ], "comment": "chewing; mastication\ndigestion (e.g. of words); assimilation; comprehension; appreciation" },
	{ "question": "和える", "answers": [ "あえる" ], "comment": "to dress (vegetables, salad, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "咎める", "answers": [ "とがめる" ], "comment": "to blame; to reproach; to censure; to rebuke; to reprove; to find fault; to take to task; to criticize; to criticise\nto question (a suspect); to challenge\nto aggravate (an injury); to be aggravated; to get inflamed\nto prick (one's conscience)" },
	{ "question": "唯々諾々", "answers": [ "いいだくだく" ], "comment": "quite willingly; readily; with acquiescence" },
	{ "question": "唸る", "answers": [ "うなる" ], "comment": "to groan; to moan\nto roar; to howl; to growl\nto hum (e.g. engine, wires in wind); to buzz; to sough; low, dull sound\nto ooh and aah (in admiration)\nto sing in a strong, low voice (esp. traditional chant or recitation)" },
	{ "question": "啄む", "answers": [ "ついばむ" ], "comment": "to pick at; to peck at" },
	{ "question": "啓蟄", "answers": [ "けいちつ" ], "comment": "\"awakening of insects\" solar term (approx. Mar. 6, the day on which hibernating insects are said to come out of the ground)" },
	{ "question": "嗚呼", "answers": [ "ああ" ], "comment": "Ah!; Oh!; Alas!\nYes; Indeed; That is correct\nHey!; Yo!\nUh huh; Yeah yeah; Right; Gotcha" },
	{ "question": "嗚咽", "answers": [ "おえつ" ], "comment": "sobbing; weeping; groaning; fit of crying" },
	{ "question": "嗜む", "answers": [ "たしなむ" ], "comment": "to have a taste for; to be fond of; to have an interest in (e.g. a hobby)\nto be modest; to be prudent" },
	{ "question": "嗜好", "answers": [ "しこう" ], "comment": "taste; liking; preference" },
	{ "question": "嗽", "answers": [ "うがい" ], "comment": "gargling; rinsing one's mouth" },
	{ "question": "嘗て", "answers": [ "かつて" ], "comment": "once; before; formerly; ever; former; ex-\nnever yet; never before; first time; still not happened" },
	{ "question": "嘲る", "answers": [ "あざける" ], "comment": "to scoff; to laugh at; to make fun of; to ridicule; to jeer at" },
	{ "question": "嘶く", "answers": [ "いななく" ], "comment": "to neigh" },
	{ "question": "嚆矢", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "whistling arrow used to signal the start of battle\nstart (e.g. of a movement); beginning; dawn" },
	{ "question": "嚇す", "answers": [ "おどす" ], "comment": "to threaten; to menace; to bully\nto threaten; to menace" },
	{ "question": "四方山話", "answers": [ "よもやまばなし" ], "comment": "talk about various topics" },
	{ "question": "四股", "answers": [ "しこ" ], "comment": "wrestler's ceremonial leg raising and stomping" },
	{ "question": "因む", "answers": [ "ちなむ" ], "comment": "to be associated (with); to be connected (with)" },
	{ "question": "団栗", "answers": [ "どんぐり" ], "comment": "acorn" },
	{ "question": "団欒", "answers": [ "だんらん" ], "comment": "sitting together in a circle; happy circle; harmony" },
	{ "question": "囮", "answers": [ "おとり" ], "comment": "decoy (for hunting); stool\nlure; decoy; stool pigeon; trap" },
	{ "question": "困憊", "answers": [ "こんぱい" ], "comment": "exhaustion; fatigue" },
	{ "question": "固唾", "answers": [ "かたず" ], "comment": "saliva held in one's mouth during times of tension" },
	{ "question": "土壇場", "answers": [ "どたんば" ], "comment": "last moment; eleventh hour\nplatform made of dirt used to perform executions (decapitations) in the Edo period" },
	{ "question": "土竜", "answers": [ "もぐら" ], "comment": "mole (Talpidae spp., esp. the small Japanese mole, Mogera imaizumii)" },
	{ "question": "土筆", "answers": [ "つくし" ], "comment": "fertile shoot of field horsetail\nwooden stick with a burned tip (used to create underdrawings)" },
	{ "question": "均す", "answers": [ "ならす" ], "comment": "to make even; to make smooth; to make level\nto average" },
	{ "question": "均衡", "answers": [ "きんこう" ], "comment": "equilibrium; balance" },
	{ "question": "坩堝", "answers": [ "るつぼ" ], "comment": "crucible; (melting) pot" },
	{ "question": "塩梅", "answers": [ "あんばい" ], "comment": "seasoning; flavour; flavor\nserving one's lord well (of a retainer)\nseasoning; flavour; flavor\ncondition; state; situation\narrangement; assignment; adjustment" },
	{ "question": "墳る", "answers": [ "うごもる" ] },
	{ "question": "夢現", "answers": [ "ゆめうつつ" ], "comment": "half asleep and half awake; trance\ndream and reality" },
	{ "question": "大童", "answers": [ "おおわらわ" ], "comment": "strenuous efforts; hard fighting" },
	{ "question": "大鋸屑", "answers": [ "おがくず" ], "comment": "sawdust" },
	{ "question": "天婦羅", "answers": [ "てんぷら" ], "comment": "tempura; deep-fried fish and vegetables in a light batter" },
	{ "question": "天晴", "answers": [ "あっぱれ" ], "comment": "splendid; praiseworthy; admirable; brilliant\nwell done!; bravo!" },
	{ "question": "太々しい", "answers": [ "ふてぶてしい" ], "comment": "impudent; brazen; shameless; bold" },
	{ "question": "奇天烈", "answers": [ "きてれつ" ], "comment": "very strange; odd; queer" },
	{ "question": "奇譚", "answers": [ "きたん" ], "comment": "mysterious story" },
	{ "question": "奢る", "answers": [ "おごる" ], "comment": "to give (someone) a treat\nto be extravagant; to live luxuriously\nto be proud; to be haughty" },
	{ "question": "奢侈", "answers": [ "しゃし" ], "comment": "luxury; extravagance" },
	{ "question": "女将", "answers": [ "おかみ" ], "comment": "mistress; landlady; hostess; proprietress" },
	{ "question": "女衒", "answers": [ "ぜげん" ], "comment": "someone who makes their living selling women into prostitution; pimp; procurer" },
	{ "question": "好々爺", "answers": [ "こうこうや" ], "comment": "good-natured old man" },
	{ "question": "好事家", "answers": [ "こうずか" ], "comment": "dilettante; person of fantastic taste" },
	{ "question": "好悪", "answers": [ "こうお" ], "comment": "likes and dislikes" },
	{ "question": "委ねる", "answers": [ "ゆだねる" ], "comment": "to entrust (a matter) to; to leave to\nto abandon oneself to (e.g. pleasure); to yield to (e.g. anger); to devote oneself to" },
	{ "question": "姦しい", "answers": [ "かしましい" ], "comment": "noisy; boisterous" },
	{ "question": "娑婆", "answers": [ "しゃば" ], "comment": "this world; this life\nthe free world (outside of prison, the army, red light district, etc.)\nthis corrupt world; present world" },
	{ "question": "娶る", "answers": [ "めとる" ], "comment": "to marry (a woman); to take to wife" },
	{ "question": "嫉む", "answers": [ "そねむ" ], "comment": "to be jealous of; to envy; to begrudge" },
	{ "question": "安穏", "answers": [ "あんのん" ], "comment": "peace; quiet; tranquility; tranquillity" },
	{ "question": "宣う", "answers": [ "のたまう" ] },
	{ "question": "家鴨", "answers": [ "あひる" ], "comment": "domestic duck" },
	{ "question": "容易い", "answers": [ "たやすい" ], "comment": "easy; simple; light" },
	{ "question": "寄席", "answers": [ "よせ" ], "comment": "entertainment hall (for rakugo, manzai, magic, music, etc.); vaudeville theater (theatre); music hall" },
	{ "question": "寧ろ", "answers": [ "むしろ" ], "comment": "rather; better; instead" },
	{ "question": "寸毫", "answers": [ "すんごう" ], "comment": "a bit; very little" },
	{ "question": "小火", "answers": [ "ぼや" ], "comment": "small fire" },
	{ "question": "小賢しい", "answers": [ "こざかしい" ], "comment": "clever; shrewd; crafty; cunning; pretentious; impertinent; insolent" },
	{ "question": "尤も", "answers": [ "もっとも" ], "comment": "most; extremely\nbut then; although; though\nreasonable; natural; just" },
	{ "question": "山茶花", "answers": [ "さざんか" ], "comment": "sasanqua (Camellia sasanqua)" },
	{ "question": "山葵", "answers": [ "わさび" ], "comment": "wasabi (Wasabia japonica)" },
	{ "question": "山車", "answers": [ "だし" ], "comment": "parade float; festival float\ndecorative portable shrine; float used in festivals\nwheel tree (Trochodendron araloides)" },
	{ "question": "崇める", "answers": [ "あがめる" ], "comment": "to revere; to respect; to worship" },
	{ "question": "嵌まる", "answers": [ "はまる" ], "comment": "to fit; to get into; to go into\nto be fit for (a job, etc.); to be suited for; to satisfy (conditions)\nto fall into; to plunge into; to get stuck; to get caught\nto be deceived; to be taken in; to fall into a trap\nto be addicted to; to be deep into; to be crazy about; to be stuck on" },
	{ "question": "巣窟", "answers": [ "そうくつ" ], "comment": "den; haunt; hangout; home" },
	{ "question": "市井", "answers": [ "しせい" ], "comment": "the street; the town" },
	{ "question": "布袋", "answers": [ "ほてい" ], "comment": "cloth bag\npot-bellied god of good fortune" },
	{ "question": "師走", "answers": [ "しわす" ], "comment": "twelfth month (esp. of the lunar calendar); December" },
	{ "question": "帰依", "answers": [ "きえ" ], "comment": "devotion; (religious) conversion" },
	{ "question": "常夏", "answers": [ "とこなつ" ], "comment": "everlasting summer" },
	{ "question": "干瓢", "answers": [ "かんぴょう" ], "comment": "strips of dried gourd" },
	{ "question": "幸先", "answers": [ "さいさき" ], "comment": "omen; sign (usually good)" },
	{ "question": "廃る", "answers": [ "すたる" ], "comment": "to go out of use; to become obsolete; to die out; to go out of fashion" },
	{ "question": "弑逆", "answers": [ "しいぎゃく" ], "comment": "murder of one's own lord or father" },
	{ "question": "弔意", "answers": [ "ちょうい" ], "comment": "condolence; sympathy; mourning" },
	{ "question": "弛む", "answers": [ "たるむ" ], "comment": "to become loose; to slacken (e.g. rope)\nto become less tense; to relax; to let one's guard down\nto slacken (e.g. coldness, supervision); to become lax\nto become softer (e.g. ground, facial expression); (of ice) to partially melt\nto decrease (e.g. speed)\n(of a market price) to go down slightly\nto slacken; to loosen; to relax; to droop (e.g. loose or flabby skin); to sag (ceiling)\nto slack off (e.g. one's work, attention); to not put one's heart in" },
	{ "question": "弛緩", "answers": [ "しかん" ], "comment": "relaxation (e.g. of muscles); becoming flaccid" },
	{ "question": "強面", "answers": [ "こわもて" ], "comment": "hard-faced; aggressive; fierce look; frightening look" },
	{ "question": "彷徨う", "answers": [ "さまよう" ], "comment": "to loiter; to putter; to prowl; to wander about; to roam about; to knock around" },
	{ "question": "彼我", "answers": [ "ひが" ], "comment": "self and others; this and that; both sides; oneself and one's opponent; he and I" },
	{ "question": "徒に", "answers": [ "いたずらに" ] },
	{ "question": "御伽噺", "answers": [ "おとぎばなし" ], "comment": "fairy-tale; nursery-tale" },
	{ "question": "微塵子", "answers": [ "みじんこ" ], "comment": "water flea (Daphnia spp.)" },
	{ "question": "微酔い", "answers": [ "ほろよい" ], "comment": "slight intoxication; being tipsy" },
	{ "question": "心太", "answers": [ "ところてん" ], "comment": "gelidium jelly strips (made from agar-agar)\nprostate orgasm" },
	{ "question": "忌々しい", "answers": [ "いまいましい" ], "comment": "annoying; provoking" },
	{ "question": "忌憚", "answers": [ "きたん" ], "comment": "reserve; modesty" },
	{ "question": "忸怩", "answers": [ "じくじ" ], "comment": "bashful; shameful; ashamed" },
	{ "question": "忽ち", "answers": [ "たちまち" ], "comment": "in an instant; in a moment; immediately; right away; at once\nsuddenly; all of a sudden; all at once" },
	{ "question": "忽然", "answers": [ "こつぜん" ], "comment": "sudden; unexpected" },
	{ "question": "怪訝", "answers": [ "けげん" ], "comment": "dubious; puzzled; suspicious" },
	{ "question": "怯む", "answers": [ "ひるむ" ], "comment": "to falter; to flinch (from); to recoil (from); to quail (at)" },
	{ "question": "恍惚", "answers": [ "こうこつ" ], "comment": "ecstasy; trance" },
	{ "question": "恣意", "answers": [ "しい" ], "comment": "arbitrariness" },
	{ "question": "息吹", "answers": [ "いぶき" ], "comment": "breath\nsign (of something new and fresh); breath (metaphor)" },
	{ "question": "恰幅", "answers": [ "かっぷく" ], "comment": "physique; bodily build" },
	{ "question": "悉く", "answers": [ "ことごとく" ], "comment": "altogether; entirely" },
	{ "question": "悖る", "answers": [ "もとる" ], "comment": "to go against; to act contrary to; to deviate from; to oppose" },
	{ "question": "悪戯", "answers": [ "いたずら" ], "comment": "mischief; prank; trick; practical joke\npastime; hobby\nplaying with (a lighter, etc.); fooling around with; messing around with; amusing oneself with; tampering with\nlewd behaviour; sexual misconduct; sexual assault; molestation; rape\noffensive joke" },
	{ "question": "悶える", "answers": [ "もだえる" ], "comment": "to be in agony; to worry" },
	{ "question": "悼む", "answers": [ "いたむ" ], "comment": "to grieve over; to mourn; to lament" },
	{ "question": "意固地", "answers": [ "いこじ" ], "comment": "obstinate; stubborn; obdurate; headstrong; willful; perverse" },
	{ "question": "意気地", "answers": [ "いくじ" ], "comment": "self-respect; self-confidence; guts; backbone" },
	{ "question": "慇懃", "answers": [ "いんぎん" ], "comment": "courtesy; intimacy; friendship" },
	{ "question": "慟哭", "answers": [ "どうこく" ], "comment": "wailing; lamentation" },
	{ "question": "憔悴", "answers": [ "しょうすい" ], "comment": "emaciation; haggardness; wasting away\nexhaustion; tiredness" },
	{ "question": "憚る", "answers": [ "はばかる" ], "comment": "to hesitate; to have scruples; to be afraid of what others may think\nto lord it over; to have great influence" },
	{ "question": "憾み", "answers": [ "うらみ" ], "comment": "resentment; grudge; malice; bitterness\nmatter for regret; regret" },
	{ "question": "所以", "answers": [ "ゆえん" ], "comment": "reason; way of doing; cause; grounds" },
	{ "question": "所為", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "act; deed; one's doing\nconsequence; outcome; result; blame" },
	{ "question": "所縁", "answers": [ "ゆかり" ], "comment": "related to (some person or place); affinity; connection" },
	{ "question": "所謂", "answers": [ "いわゆる" ], "comment": "what is called; as it is called; the so-called; so to speak" },
	{ "question": "手練", "answers": [ "てだれ" ], "comment": "skill; dexterity; master hand\nmeans of deceiving another" },
	{ "question": "払拭", "answers": [ "ふっしょく" ], "comment": "wiping out; sweeping away" },
	{ "question": "抗う", "answers": [ "あらがう" ], "comment": "to go against; to fight against; to oppose; to resist; to deny" },
	{ "question": "押捺", "answers": [ "おうなつ" ], "comment": "sealing (document)" },
	{ "question": "拗ねる", "answers": [ "すねる" ], "comment": "to be peevish; to sulk; to pout" },
	{ "question": "招聘", "answers": [ "しょうへい" ], "comment": "(courteous) invitation; call\nto invite (with the utmost courtesy, e.g. an expert or professor to give a lecture)" },
	{ "question": "拿捕", "answers": [ "だほ" ], "comment": "capture; seizure\nmilitary capture of a foreign vessel; making a prize of" },
	{ "question": "捏造", "answers": [ "ねつぞう" ], "comment": "fabrication; forgery; falsehood; hoax" },
	{ "question": "掠奪", "answers": [ "りゃくだつ" ], "comment": "pillage; plunder; looting; robbery" },
	{ "question": "推敲", "answers": [ "すいこう" ], "comment": "polishing (e.g. essay); revision; elaboration; refinement; improvement" },
	{ "question": "揶揄", "answers": [ "やゆ" ], "comment": "banter; raillery; tease; ridicule; banter with" },
	{ "question": "搦め手", "answers": [ "からめて" ], "comment": "rear gate (esp. of castle); back entrance\none who arrests\nforce attacking the rear of a castle\n(opponent's) weak point" },
	{ "question": "教唆", "answers": [ "きょうさ" ], "comment": "instigation" },
	{ "question": "数多", "answers": [ "あまた" ], "comment": "many; a lot; much; multitude" },
	{ "question": "斡旋", "answers": [ "あっせん" ], "comment": "kind offices; services; through the good offices of; influence\nintercession; mediation" },
	{ "question": "旗幟", "answers": [ "きし" ], "comment": "flag; banner; ensign; emblem" },
	{ "question": "時化", "answers": [ "しけ" ], "comment": "stormy weather (at sea)\npoor catch of fish (due to stormy seas)\npoor turn-out; recession" },
	{ "question": "時雨", "answers": [ "しぐれ" ], "comment": "rain shower in late autumn (fall) or early winter\nseasonable rain" },
	{ "question": "晒す", "answers": [ "さらす" ], "comment": "to expose (to the sun, public, danger, etc.)\nto bleach; to refine\nto rinse (vegetables); to soak\nto sentence someone to public humiliation" },
	{ "question": "暖簾", "answers": [ "のれん" ], "comment": "(short) sign curtain hung at shop entrance\nreputation (of a store); goodwill" },
	{ "question": "曰く", "answers": [ "いわく" ], "comment": "pretext; history; past; story\naccording to ...; ... says" },
	{ "question": "曲者", "answers": [ "くせもの" ], "comment": "ruffian; villain; knave; thief; suspicious fellow\npeculiar person; idiosyncratic person; stubborn fellow\ntricky thing; something that is more than it seems\nexpert; master; highly skilled person\ngoblin; apparition; monster; ghost; phantom; spectre; specter" },
	{ "question": "更迭", "answers": [ "こうてつ" ], "comment": "change; shake-up; reshuffle (e.g. of a cabinet); dismissal (e.g. of a minister); exchanging places" },
	{ "question": "有耶無耶", "answers": [ "うやむや" ], "comment": "indefinite; hazy; vague; unsettled; undecided" },
	{ "question": "有象無象", "answers": [ "うぞうむぞう" ], "comment": "mob; the masses; rabble; riffraff" },
	{ "question": "木偶", "answers": [ "でく" ], "comment": "wooden figure; wooden doll; puppet\nblockhead; good-for-nothing; fool" },
	{ "question": "未曽有", "answers": [ "みぞう" ], "comment": "unprecedented; unheard of" },
	{ "question": "朱鷺", "answers": [ "とき" ], "comment": "Japanese crested ibis (Nipponia nippon); crested ibis" },
	{ "question": "杏", "answers": [ "あんず" ], "comment": "apricot (Prunus armeniaca)" },
	{ "question": "杜撰", "answers": [ "ずさん" ], "comment": "careless; sloppy; faulty\nusing unreliable sources (in a piece of writing); piece of writing with unreliable sources or many errors" },
	{ "question": "東雲", "answers": [ "しののめ" ], "comment": "daybreak; dawn" },
	{ "question": "林檎", "answers": [ "りんご" ], "comment": "apple (fruit)\napple tree (Malus pumila)" },
	{ "question": "柊", "answers": [ "ひいらぎ" ], "comment": "holly olive (Osmanthus heterophyllus); false holly\nholly\nspotnape ponyfish (Leiognathus nuchalis)" },
	{ "question": "栗鼠", "answers": [ "りす" ], "comment": "squirrel (excluding flying squirrels)\nJapanese squirrel (Sciurus lis)" },
	{ "question": "栞", "answers": [ "しおり" ], "comment": "bookmark\nguidebook" },
	{ "question": "案山子", "answers": [ "かかし" ], "comment": "scarecrow\nfigurehead" },
	{ "question": "梟", "answers": [ "ふくろう" ], "comment": "owl (esp. the Ural owl, Strix uralensis)" },
	{ "question": "梯子", "answers": [ "はしご" ], "comment": "ladder\nstairs\ngoing to several places in succession (e.g. barhopping)" },
	{ "question": "椿事", "answers": [ "ちんじ" ], "comment": "strange occurrence; unusual occurrence; unexpected occurrence" },
	{ "question": "概ね", "answers": [ "おおむね" ], "comment": "in general; generally; mostly; roughly; largely; mainly; on the whole; by and large\ngist; point; main idea" },
	{ "question": "権化", "answers": [ "ごんげ" ], "comment": "incarnation (of Buddha or bodhisattva); avatar\nembodiment (as in \"embodiment of evil\"); incarnation; personification" },
	{ "question": "欠伸", "answers": [ "あくび" ], "comment": "yawn; yawning" },
	{ "question": "此処", "answers": [ "ここ" ], "comment": "here (place physically close to the speaker, place pointed by the speaker while explaining); this place\nthese last (followed by a duration noun and a past sentence: time period before the present time of the speaker)\nthese next ... (followed by a duration noun and a non past sentence: time period after the present time of the speaker); the next ..." },
	{ "question": "残滓", "answers": [ "ざんし" ], "comment": "remains; dregs; vestiges" },
	{ "question": "殲滅", "answers": [ "せんめつ" ], "comment": "extermination; annihilation" },
	{ "question": "殺める", "answers": [ "あやめる" ], "comment": "to wound; to murder" },
	{ "question": "殺戮", "answers": [ "さつりく" ], "comment": "slaughter; massacre" },
	{ "question": "殺生", "answers": [ "せっしょう" ], "comment": "killing; destruction of life\nbarbarous; callous; brutal; cruel" },
	{ "question": "殺陣", "answers": [ "たて" ], "comment": "sword battle (staged for television, etc.); sword fight" },
	{ "question": "毀損", "answers": [ "きそん" ], "comment": "damage; injury; defamation; waste" },
	{ "question": "気っ風", "answers": [ "きっぷ" ], "comment": "character; disposition; spirit; temperament" },
	{ "question": "気色ばむ", "answers": [ "けしきばむ" ], "comment": "to grow angry; to display one's anger" },
	{ "question": "気障", "answers": [ "きざ" ], "comment": "affected; smug; pompous; conceited; snobby; pretentious" },
	{ "question": "河岸", "answers": [ "かし" ], "comment": "riverbank; riverside\nfish market" },
	{ "question": "河豚", "answers": [ "ふぐ" ], "comment": "puffer fish; blow fish; fugu; globefish; swellfish" },
	{ "question": "況や", "answers": [ "いわんや" ], "comment": "much more; not to mention; not to speak of; to say nothing of; let alone" },
	{ "question": "泡沫", "answers": [ "うたかた" ], "comment": "bubble on surface of liquid\nephemeral; transient" },
	{ "question": "洒落", "answers": [ "しゃれ" ], "comment": "frank; open-hearted\njoke; pun; witticism\nsmartly dressed; stylish; fashion-conscious; refined\nimpertinent\nfresh; fashionable\nprostitute" },
	{ "question": "流布", "answers": [ "るふ" ], "comment": "circulation; dissemination" },
	{ "question": "流石", "answers": [ "さすが" ], "comment": "as one would expect\nstill; all the same\neven... (e.g. \"even a genius...\")" },
	{ "question": "流離う", "answers": [ "さすらう" ], "comment": "to wander; to roam" },
	{ "question": "浚渫", "answers": [ "しゅんせつ" ], "comment": "dredging" },
	{ "question": "浮腫む", "answers": [ "むくむ" ], "comment": "to swell; to become swollen; to be puffy (e.g. face from lack of sleep); to be bloated (esp. from fluid retention)" },
	{ "question": "浴衣", "answers": [ "ゆかた" ], "comment": "yukata (light cotton kimono worn in the summer or used as a bathrobe)" },
	{ "question": "海女", "answers": [ "あま" ], "comment": "ama; female diver (who collects shells, seaweed, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "海月", "answers": [ "くらげ" ], "comment": "jellyfish\nmedusa" },
	{ "question": "海栗", "answers": [ "うに" ], "comment": "sea urchin\nseasoned sea urchin eggs" },
	{ "question": "海豚", "answers": [ "いるか" ], "comment": "dolphin (or other small toothed whales, such as porpoises, belugas, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "海豹", "answers": [ "あざらし" ], "comment": "true seal (animal); earless seal" },
	{ "question": "淘汰", "answers": [ "とうた" ], "comment": "weeding out; elimination (e.g. of unneeded employees); culling; selection\nselection (e.g. natural selection)" },
	{ "question": "減り張り", "answers": [ "めりはり" ], "comment": "modulation (of voice)\nvariation; variety\nliveliness; full-bodied" },
	{ "question": "渾名", "answers": [ "あだな" ], "comment": "nickname" },
	{ "question": "湛える", "answers": [ "たたえる" ], "comment": "to fill (to the brim)\nto express (an emotion); to look (sad, glad); to wear (a smile)" },
	{ "question": "滲出", "answers": [ "しんしゅつ" ], "comment": "infiltration; permeation; exudation; percolation; effusion; extraction" },
	{ "question": "漁火", "answers": [ "いさりび" ], "comment": "fire for luring fish at night\nfire for luring fish at night" },
	{ "question": "演繹", "answers": [ "えんえき" ], "comment": "deductive reasoning; deduction" },
	{ "question": "漸く", "answers": [ "ようやく" ], "comment": "finally; at last\nbarely; narrowly; hardly; only just\ngradually; little by little; by degrees" },
	{ "question": "潮騒", "answers": [ "しおさい" ], "comment": "sea roar" },
	{ "question": "澪標", "answers": [ "みおつくし" ], "comment": "marks in a water channel" },
	{ "question": "澱", "answers": [ "おり" ], "comment": "stagnation; deposit; sediment; backwater\nfaltering; hesitation; pause\ndregs; lees; grounds; sediment\npool (in river)" },
	{ "question": "瀟洒", "answers": [ "しょうしゃ" ], "comment": "stylish; smart; elegant; chic; refined; trim; neat" },
	{ "question": "灰汁", "answers": [ "あく" ], "comment": "lye\nharsh taste; astringency\nscum (formed when cooking some foods)\n(excessive) strength of will" },
	{ "question": "灰燼", "answers": [ "かいじん" ], "comment": "ash; embers; complete destruction" },
	{ "question": "炯眼", "answers": [ "けいがん" ], "comment": "penetrating eyes; insightfulness" },
	{ "question": "為人", "answers": [ "ひととなり" ], "comment": "hereditary disposition; temperament; nature\nbody build" },
	{ "question": "烏賊", "answers": [ "いか" ], "comment": "cuttlefish; squid" },
	{ "question": "煉瓦", "answers": [ "れんが" ], "comment": "brick" },
	{ "question": "煌めく", "answers": [ "きらめく" ], "comment": "to glitter; to glisten; to sparkle; to twinkle; to glare; to gleam" },
	{ "question": "煙管", "answers": [ "きせる" ], "comment": "kiseru; Japanese smoking pipe\nfire tube (of a fire-tube boiler)\nchimney\n(tobacco) pipe with metal tipped stem\nstolen train ride (only paying a local fare each end)" },
	{ "question": "煤", "answers": [ "すす" ], "comment": "soot" },
	{ "question": "煽てる", "answers": [ "おだてる" ], "comment": "to flatter; to soft-soap\nto instigate; to stir up" },
	{ "question": "燻す", "answers": [ "いぶす" ], "comment": "to smoke (something); to fumigate\nto oxidize; to oxidise" },
	{ "question": "牛蒡", "answers": [ "ごぼう" ], "comment": "great burdock (Arctium lappa)" },
	{ "question": "牛車", "answers": [ "ぎっしゃ" ], "comment": "ox carriage (for Heian era nobles); oxcart" },
	{ "question": "牡蠣", "answers": [ "かき" ], "comment": "oyster; oyster shell" },
	{ "question": "狢", "answers": [ "むじな" ], "comment": "badger\nraccoon dog (Nyctereutes procyonoides)" },
	{ "question": "狼煙", "answers": [ "のろし" ], "comment": "beacon; skyrocket; signal fire; smoke signals\nstarting shot; starting signal" },
	{ "question": "狼狽", "answers": [ "ろうばい" ], "comment": "confusion; dismay; consternation; panic" },
	{ "question": "狼狽える", "answers": [ "うろたえる" ], "comment": "to be flustered; to lose one's presence of mind" },
	{ "question": "猛々しい", "answers": [ "たけだけしい" ], "comment": "ferocious; fierce\naudacious; impudent; shameless; brazen" },
	{ "question": "猛者", "answers": [ "もさ" ], "comment": "man of valour; man of valor; stalwart; tough guy; warrior" },
	{ "question": "猪口", "answers": [ "ちょこ" ], "comment": "small cup; sake cup" },
	{ "question": "猫糞", "answers": [ "ねこばば" ], "comment": "embezzlement; misappropriation; pocketing; stealing" },
	{ "question": "玄人", "answers": [ "くろうと" ], "comment": "expert; professional; master\nwoman in the nightlife business; demimondaine; geisha and prostitutes" },
	{ "question": "瑕疵", "answers": [ "かし" ], "comment": "flaw; defect; blemish" },
	{ "question": "瑪瑙", "answers": [ "めのう" ], "comment": "agate" },
	{ "question": "瓦斯", "answers": [ "がす" ], "comment": "gas (state of matter, e.g. poison gas, natural gas)\ngasoline; gas; petrol\ndense fog; thick fog\ngas stove; gas cooker; gas range\nflatulence; gas; wind; fart" },
	{ "question": "瓦礫", "answers": [ "がれき" ], "comment": "rubble; debris; wreckage" },
	{ "question": "生け贄", "answers": [ "いけにえ" ], "comment": "sacrifice (to the gods)\nvictim; scapegoat" },
	{ "question": "生憎", "answers": [ "あいにく" ], "comment": "unfortunately; Sorry, but ..." },
	{ "question": "生業", "answers": [ "なりわい" ], "comment": "occupation; calling\nlivelihood" },
	{ "question": "生粋", "answers": [ "きっすい" ], "comment": "pure; genuine; trueborn; natural-born" },
	{ "question": "疼く", "answers": [ "うずく" ], "comment": "to throb; to ache" },
	{ "question": "疾病", "answers": [ "しっぺい" ], "comment": "illness; disease" },
	{ "question": "癇癪", "answers": [ "かんしゃく" ], "comment": "passion; temper; irritability" },
	{ "question": "白湯", "answers": [ "さゆ" ], "comment": "(plain) hot water; boiled water" },
	{ "question": "百舌", "answers": [ "もず" ], "comment": "shrike (any bird of family Laniidae)\nbull-headed shrike (Lanius bucephalus); butcher bird" },
	{ "question": "百足", "answers": [ "むかで" ], "comment": "centipede" },
	{ "question": "目処", "answers": [ "めど" ], "comment": "aim; goal\nprospect; outlook" },
	{ "question": "目眩", "answers": [ "めまい" ], "comment": "dizziness; giddiness; vertigo" },
	{ "question": "目眩く", "answers": [ "めくるめく" ], "comment": "to dazzle; to blind" },
	{ "question": "相応しい", "answers": [ "ふさわしい" ], "comment": "appropriate; adequate; suitable; fitting; worthy" },
	{ "question": "相殺", "answers": [ "そうさい" ], "comment": "offset; offsetting each other; cancelling each other out; counterbalancing\nset-off; setoff" },
	{ "question": "看做す", "answers": [ "みなす" ], "comment": "to consider as; to regard (as equivalent); to deem (as); to equate" },
	{ "question": "睥睨", "answers": [ "へいげい" ], "comment": "glaring at; lording over" },
	{ "question": "睨む", "answers": [ "にらむ" ], "comment": "to glare at; to scowl at; to glower at\nto stare intensely at; to examine carefully\nto estimate; to guess; to suspect; to judge\nto keep an eye on someone (e.g. a suspicious or untrustworthy person); to watch\nto take account of; to take into consideration" },
	{ "question": "瞬く", "answers": [ "またたく", "まだたく", "まばたく", "めばたく", "しばたたく", "しばだたく", "しばたく" ], "comment": "to blink (one's eyes); to wink; to bat\nto twinkle (e.g. stars); to flicker; to waver\nto blink (one's eyes); to wink; to bat\nto blink (one's eyes); to wink; to bat" },
	{ "question": "矜持", "answers": [ "きょうじ" ], "comment": "pride; dignity; self-respect" },
	{ "question": "知己", "answers": [ "ちき" ], "comment": "acquaintance; appreciative friend" },
	{ "question": "知悉", "answers": [ "ちしつ" ], "comment": "complete knowledge" },
	{ "question": "研鑽", "answers": [ "けんさん" ], "comment": "diligent study; devoting oneself to one's studies" },
	{ "question": "硝子", "answers": [ "がらす" ], "comment": "glass; pane\nvitreous" },
	{ "question": "祇園", "answers": [ "ぎおん" ] },
	{ "question": "神輿", "answers": [ "みこし" ], "comment": "portable shrine (carried in festivals)\npalanquin\nbuttocks; lower back; waist; hips" },
	{ "question": "禊ぎ", "answers": [ "みそぎ" ] },
	{ "question": "禍々しい", "answers": [ "まがまがしい" ], "comment": "ominous; sinister; unlucky; ill-omened\nannoying\nappearing to be true" },
	{ "question": "福音", "answers": [ "ふくいん" ], "comment": "good news\ngospel (teachings or revelations of Jesus Christ)" },
	{ "question": "秋刀魚", "answers": [ "さんま" ], "comment": "Pacific saury (Cololabis saira); mackerel pike" },
	{ "question": "稀有", "answers": [ "けう" ], "comment": "rare; uncommon" },
	{ "question": "稀覯本", "answers": [ "きこうぼん" ], "comment": "rare book" },
	{ "question": "稲荷", "answers": [ "いなり" ], "comment": "Inari (god of harvests, Uka-no-Mitama)\nInari shrine; Fushimi Inari shrine (in Kyoto)\nfox (said to be messengers of Inari)\nfried tofu (said to be a favourite food of foxes)\nInari-zushi" },
	{ "question": "穿つ", "answers": [ "うがつ" ], "comment": "to drill; to bore; to pierce; to pass through\nto hit the mark; to get to the heart of (the matter); to be true to (nature)\nto put on; to wear" },
	{ "question": "窺う", "answers": [ "うかがう" ], "comment": "to peep (through); to peek; to examine (esp. covertly)\nto await (one's chance)\nto guess; to infer; to gather; to surmise" },
	{ "question": "窺く", "answers": [ "のぞく" ], "comment": "to peek (though a keyhole, gap, etc.)\nto look down into (a ravine, etc.)\nto peek into (a shop, bookstore, etc.)\nto sneak a look at; to take a quick look at\nto peep (through a telescope, microscope, etc.)\nto stick out (a scarf from a collar, etc.); to peek through (sky through a forest canopy, etc.)\nto examine (an expression); to study (a face)\nto face" },
	{ "question": "筍", "answers": [ "たけのこ" ], "comment": "bamboo shoot\ninexperienced doctor; quack" },
	{ "question": "算盤", "answers": [ "そろばん" ], "comment": "abacus" },
	{ "question": "範疇", "answers": [ "はんちゅう" ], "comment": "category" },
	{ "question": "素性", "answers": [ "すじょう" ], "comment": "birth; lineage; parentage; origin\nidentity; background; history; past\nprovenance; origin" },
	{ "question": "紫陽花", "answers": [ "あじさい" ], "comment": "bigleaf hydrangea (Hydrangea macrophylla); French hydrangea" },
	{ "question": "終ぞ", "answers": [ "ついぞ" ], "comment": "never; not at all" },
	{ "question": "終焉", "answers": [ "しゅうえん" ], "comment": "demise" },
	{ "question": "統べる", "answers": [ "すべる" ], "comment": "to control; to supervise" },
	{ "question": "緘口令", "answers": [ "かんこうれい" ], "comment": "gag order; gag rule; gag law" },
	{ "question": "縋る", "answers": [ "すがる" ], "comment": "to cling to; to hang onto\nto rely on; to depend on\nto implore; to entreat" },
	{ "question": "繋留", "answers": [ "けいりゅう" ], "comment": "mooring; anchorage" },
	{ "question": "罵る", "answers": [ "ののしる" ], "comment": "to abuse (verbally); to curse at; to shout abuse at; to speak ill of" },
	{ "question": "罷業", "answers": [ "ひぎょう" ], "comment": "strike; walkout" },
	{ "question": "罹る", "answers": [ "かかる" ], "comment": "to contract (a disease); to suffer from" },
	{ "question": "罹災", "answers": [ "りさい" ], "comment": "suffering (from a calamity); affliction" },
	{ "question": "美人局", "answers": [ "つつもたせ" ], "comment": "scheme in which a man and woman trick another man into a compromising situation for blackmail; badger game" },
	{ "question": "羨望", "answers": [ "せんぼう" ], "comment": "envy" },
	{ "question": "義捐金", "answers": [ "ぎえんきん" ], "comment": "donation money (esp. disaster relief or charity); contribution" },
	{ "question": "翳す", "answers": [ "かざす" ], "comment": "to hold up over one's head; to hold aloft\nto hold one's hands out (e.g. towards a fire)\nto shade one's eyes, face, etc." },
	{ "question": "老舗", "answers": [ "しにせ" ], "comment": "old shop; shop of long standing\nwell-established; first of the kind; veteran" },
	{ "question": "耄碌", "answers": [ "もうろく" ], "comment": "senility; decrepitude; dotage" },
	{ "question": "耽る", "answers": [ "ふける" ], "comment": "to indulge in; to give oneself up to; to be obsessed by\nto be engrossed in; to be lost in; to be absorbed in" },
	{ "question": "耽溺", "answers": [ "たんでき" ], "comment": "indulgence (e.g. in alcohol, women, etc.)\ndebauchery; dissipation" },
	{ "question": "育む", "answers": [ "はぐくむ" ], "comment": "to raise; to bring up; to rear\nto cultivate; to foster; to nurture" },
	{ "question": "胡坐", "answers": [ "あぐら" ], "comment": "sitting cross-legged (i.e. Indian style)" },
	{ "question": "胡散臭い", "answers": [ "うさんくさい" ], "comment": "suspicious-looking; shady; questionable; dubious; fishy" },
	{ "question": "胡桃", "answers": [ "くるみ" ], "comment": "walnut (Juglans spp., esp. Juglans regia)" },
	{ "question": "脚立", "answers": [ "きゃたつ" ], "comment": "stepladder; steps" },
	{ "question": "腹癒せ", "answers": [ "はらいせ" ], "comment": "retaliation; revenge" },
	{ "question": "膠着", "answers": [ "こうちゃく" ], "comment": "agglutination; adhesion\ndeadlock; stalemate; standstill" },
	{ "question": "膾炙", "answers": [ "かいしゃ" ], "comment": "household word; universal praise" },
	{ "question": "自惚れ", "answers": [ "うぬぼれ" ], "comment": "pretension; conceit; hubris" },
	{ "question": "般若", "answers": [ "はんにゃ" ], "comment": "prajna; wisdom required to attain enlightenment\nnoh mask of a grinning, horned demoness (represents a woman's rage and jealousy)\nfamily crest designed after the Hannya noh mask\ndreadful face (esp. of a woman driven mad by jealousy); terrifying facial expression" },
	{ "question": "艱難", "answers": [ "かんなん" ], "comment": "hardships; privations; difficulties" },
	{ "question": "花魁", "answers": [ "おいらん" ], "comment": "courtesan; prostitute; oiran" },
	{ "question": "苛々", "answers": [ "いらいら" ], "comment": "getting nervous; irritation" },
	{ "question": "苛む", "answers": [ "さいなむ" ], "comment": "to torment; to torture; to harass" },
	{ "question": "若人", "answers": [ "わこうど" ], "comment": "young person" },
	{ "question": "草鞋", "answers": [ "わらじ" ], "comment": "straw sandals" },
	{ "question": "荼毘", "answers": [ "だび" ], "comment": "cremation" },
	{ "question": "莫迦", "answers": [ "ばか" ], "comment": "fool; idiot\ntrivial matter; folly; absurdity\nfoolish; stupid; dull; absurd; ridiculous\nMactra chinensis (species of trough shell)" },
	{ "question": "華奢", "answers": [ "きゃしゃ" ], "comment": "dainty; delicate; slender; slim and elegant\nfragile (e.g. furniture); delicate; frail\nlavish; luxurious; showy; gaudy" },
	{ "question": "葡萄", "answers": [ "ぶどう" ], "comment": "grape; grapevine" },
	{ "question": "蒐集", "answers": [ "しゅうしゅう" ], "comment": "gathering up; collection; accumulation" },
	{ "question": "蒲公英", "answers": [ "たんぽぽ" ], "comment": "dandelion (esp. species Taraxacum platycarpum)" },
	{ "question": "蓋し", "answers": [ "けだし" ], "comment": "perhaps; probably" },
	{ "question": "蔑ろ", "answers": [ "ないがしろ" ], "comment": "(a) slight; disrespect; making light (of); neglect" },
	{ "question": "蔓延る", "answers": [ "はびこる" ], "comment": "to become overgrown; to grow thick\nto spread; to run rampant; to thrive; to prevail; to become powerful" },
	{ "question": "蔕", "answers": [ "へた", "ほぞ" ], "comment": "calyx" },
	{ "question": "蕨", "answers": [ "わらび" ], "comment": "bracken" },
	{ "question": "薫陶", "answers": [ "くんとう" ], "comment": "education; training; discipline" },
	{ "question": "蘇る", "answers": [ "よみがえる" ], "comment": "to be resurrected; to be resuscitated; to be rehabilitated; to be revived; to be refreshed; to be restored\nto be recalled (e.g. memories); to be brought back" },
	{ "question": "蘊蓄", "answers": [ "うんちく" ], "comment": "great erudition; extensive knowledge; one's vast stock of knowledge" },
	{ "question": "虚仮", "answers": [ "こけ" ], "comment": "folly; fool" },
	{ "question": "虫酸", "answers": [ "むしず" ], "comment": "heartburn\nstrong sense of disgust" },
	{ "question": "虱", "answers": [ "しらみ" ], "comment": "louse (esp. a sucking louse); lice" },
	{ "question": "蛇蠍", "answers": [ "だかつ" ], "comment": "serpent (snake) and scorpion\ndetestation" },
	{ "question": "蝋燭", "answers": [ "ろうそく" ], "comment": "candle" },
	{ "question": "蝕む", "answers": [ "むしばむ" ], "comment": "to be worm-eaten; to be eaten by worms\nto affect adversely; to spoil; to ruin; to undermine; to gnaw at (one's heart, body, etc.); to eat into; to destroy" },
	{ "question": "蝙蝠", "answers": [ "こうもり" ], "comment": "bat (Chiroptera spp.)\numbrella\nopportunist; turncoat" },
	{ "question": "蝦蟇", "answers": [ "がま" ], "comment": "toad (esp. the Japanese toad, Bufo japonicus)" },
	{ "question": "蝮", "answers": [ "まむし" ], "comment": "pit viper (esp. the mamushi, Gloydius blomhoffi)" },
	{ "question": "蝶番", "answers": [ "ちょうつがい" ], "comment": "hinge (e.g. on a door)\njoint (esp. an anatomical joint)" },
	{ "question": "蝸牛", "answers": [ "かたつむり" ], "comment": "snail\ncochlea" },
	{ "question": "蠍", "answers": [ "さそり" ], "comment": "scorpion (Scorpiones spp.)" },
	{ "question": "蠕動", "answers": [ "ぜんどう" ], "comment": "vermiculation; peristalsis; crawling like a worm" },
	{ "question": "蠢く", "answers": [ "うごめく" ], "comment": "to wriggle; to squirm; to crawl like a worm" },
	{ "question": "蠱惑", "answers": [ "こわく" ], "comment": "fascination; glamour; glamor; enchantment; seduction" },
	{ "question": "行脚", "answers": [ "あんぎゃ" ], "comment": "pilgrimage; traveling on foot" },
	{ "question": "衒う", "answers": [ "てらう" ], "comment": "to show off; to parade; to pretend" },
	{ "question": "袈裟", "answers": [ "けさ" ], "comment": "kasaya; monk's stole\nwearing an article of clothing in the same manner as a kasaya (i.e. draped over one shoulder)" },
	{ "question": "褪せる", "answers": [ "あせる" ], "comment": "to fade; to discolor; to discolour" },
	{ "question": "襤褸", "answers": [ "ぼろ" ], "comment": "rag; scrap; tattered clothes\nfault (esp. in a pretense, pretence); defect\nrun-down; shabby; junky" },
	{ "question": "西瓜", "answers": [ "すいか" ], "comment": "watermelon (Citrullus lanatus)" },
	{ "question": "解脱", "answers": [ "げだつ" ], "comment": "being liberated from earthly desires and the woes of man; (reaching) nirvana; moksha; mukti" },
	{ "question": "言質", "answers": [ "げんち" ], "comment": "commitment; pledge; promise" },
	{ "question": "訝る", "answers": [ "いぶかる" ], "comment": "to wonder; to puzzle oneself about; to feel anxious about; to suspect" },
	{ "question": "許嫁", "answers": [ "いいなずけ" ], "comment": "fiance; fiancee" },
	{ "question": "語彙", "answers": [ "ごい" ], "comment": "vocabulary; lexicon; lexis; terminology" },
	{ "question": "読経", "answers": [ "どきょう" ], "comment": "sutra chanting" },
	{ "question": "誰何", "answers": [ "すいか" ], "comment": "challenging (an unknown person); asking a person's identity" },
	{ "question": "諍い", "answers": [ "いさかい" ], "comment": "quarrel; dispute; argument" },
	{ "question": "諧謔", "answers": [ "かいぎゃく" ], "comment": "joke; jest; banter" },
	{ "question": "諫める", "answers": [ "いさめる" ], "comment": "to remonstrate; to admonish (someone) for; to advise (someone) not to; to warn against" },
	{ "question": "諫言", "answers": [ "かんげん" ], "comment": "admonition; remonstrance; expostulation" },
	{ "question": "謀", "answers": [ "はかりごと" ], "comment": "plan; strategy" },
	{ "question": "謂れ", "answers": [ "いわれ" ], "comment": "reason; cause\nhistory; origin" },
	{ "question": "讒言", "answers": [ "ざんげん" ], "comment": "false charge; slander; defamation" },
	{ "question": "貪る", "answers": [ "むさぼる" ], "comment": "to covet; to crave; to lust insatiably for\nto indulge in; to devour greedily" },
	{ "question": "貶す", "answers": [ "けなす" ], "comment": "to speak ill of; to disparage" },
	{ "question": "貶める", "answers": [ "おとしめる" ], "comment": "to show contempt for; to look down upon; to have a low opinion of\nto cause to fall; to make decline" },
	{ "question": "賄賂", "answers": [ "わいろ" ], "comment": "bribe; sweetener; douceur" },
	{ "question": "賢しら", "answers": [ "さかしら" ], "comment": "impertinent" },
	{ "question": "質す", "answers": [ "ただす" ], "comment": "to enquire of someone about something (inquire); to question" },
	{ "question": "贔屓", "answers": [ "ひいき" ], "comment": "favour; favor; patronage; partiality; patron\nfavourite; favorite\nliking something; being partial to something; -phile" },
	{ "question": "贖う", "answers": [ "あがなう" ], "comment": "to atone for; to expiate; to redeem; to make up for; to compensate for" },
	{ "question": "贖罪", "answers": [ "しょくざい" ], "comment": "atonement\nthe Atonement (of Jesus Christ)" },
	{ "question": "趨勢", "answers": [ "すうせい" ], "comment": "tendency; trend" },
	{ "question": "足袋", "answers": [ "たび" ], "comment": "tabi; Japanese socks (with split toe)" },
	{ "question": "跋扈", "answers": [ "ばっこ" ], "comment": "rampancy; prevalence; domination" },
	{ "question": "跪く", "answers": [ "ひざまずく" ], "comment": "to kneel" },
	{ "question": "跳梁", "answers": [ "ちょうりょう" ], "comment": "jumping about; rampancy; domination" },
	{ "question": "蹂躙", "answers": [ "じゅうりん" ], "comment": "trampling down; overrunning; infringement; violation" },
	{ "question": "躊躇", "answers": [ "ちゅうちょ" ], "comment": "hesitation; indecision; vacillation" },
	{ "question": "躊躇う", "answers": [ "ためらう" ], "comment": "to hesitate; to waver" },
	{ "question": "身動ぎ", "answers": [ "みじろぎ" ], "comment": "stirring; slight movement" },
	{ "question": "軋轢", "answers": [ "あつれき" ], "comment": "friction; discord; strife" },
	{ "question": "輜重", "answers": [ "しちょう" ] },
	{ "question": "轍", "answers": [ "わだち" ], "comment": "rut; wheel track; furrow" },
	{ "question": "辟易", "answers": [ "へきえき" ], "comment": "to be stumped; to be nonplussed; to be disconcerted; to dumbfounded\nto be fed up with; to be tired of; to find unable to bear\nto wince; to shrink back; to cringe" },
	{ "question": "辣腕", "answers": [ "らつわん" ], "comment": "shrewdness; tact" },
	{ "question": "辿る", "answers": [ "たどる" ], "comment": "to follow (road); to pursue (course); to follow up; to follow (hyperlink)" },
	{ "question": "逆鱗", "answers": [ "げきりん" ], "comment": "imperial wrath; one's superior's anger" },
	{ "question": "逞しい", "answers": [ "たくましい" ], "comment": "burly; strong; sturdy\nindomitable; indefatigable; strong-willed; resolute; bold\nrobust (vitality, appetite, economic growth, etc.); strong" },
	{ "question": "造詣", "answers": [ "ぞうけい" ], "comment": "deep knowledge; attainments; scholarship" },
	{ "question": "逢瀬", "answers": [ "おうせ" ], "comment": "rendezvous; tryst; (lover's) meeting; (secret) date" },
	{ "question": "進捗", "answers": [ "しんちょく" ], "comment": "progress; being under way" },
	{ "question": "遊説", "answers": [ "ゆうぜい" ], "comment": "election tour; election campaign; stumping" },
	{ "question": "遍く", "answers": [ "あまねく" ], "comment": "widely; generally; universally; far and wide" },
	{ "question": "遡る", "answers": [ "さかのぼる" ], "comment": "to go upstream\nto go back (in time, to origin); to date back to; to trace back to; to make retroactive" },
	{ "question": "遡行", "answers": [ "そこう" ], "comment": "going upstream; sailing against the current" },
	{ "question": "邂逅", "answers": [ "かいこう" ], "comment": "chance meeting" },
	{ "question": "鄙びた", "answers": [ "ひなびた" ], "comment": "rustic; rural; countrified" },
	{ "question": "醍醐味", "answers": [ "だいごみ" ], "comment": "the real pleasure (of something); the real thrill; the true charm\nflavour of ghee; delicious taste\nBuddha's gracious teachings" },
	{ "question": "釣果", "answers": [ "ちょうか" ], "comment": "catch (fishing); amount of fish caught; caught fish" },
	{ "question": "銀杏", "answers": [ "ぎんなん" ], "comment": "ginkgo (Ginkgo biloba); gingko; maidenhair tree\nginkgo nut; gingko nut" },
	{ "question": "銅鑼", "answers": [ "どら" ], "comment": "gong; tam-tam" },
	{ "question": "鋳造", "answers": [ "ちゅうぞう" ], "comment": "casting; founding; minting" },
	{ "question": "鑑", "answers": [ "かがみ" ], "comment": "model; pattern" },
	{ "question": "鑑みる", "answers": [ "かんがみる" ], "comment": "to heed; to take into account; to bear in mind; to learn from; to take warning from; in view of; in the light of" },
	{ "question": "長ける", "answers": [ "たける" ], "comment": "to excel at; to be proficient at\nto grow old\nto ripen\nto rise high (e.g. the sun)" },
	{ "question": "開闢", "answers": [ "かいびゃく" ], "comment": "beginnings; creation; founding (of empire)" },
	{ "question": "閏年", "answers": [ "うるうどし" ], "comment": "leap year" },
	{ "question": "阿吽", "answers": [ "あうん" ], "comment": "Om; Aun; syllable representing the primordial trinity of Vishnu, Shiva and Brahma\ninspiration and expiration; respiration; alpha and omega" },
	{ "question": "阿漕", "answers": [ "あこぎ" ], "comment": "greed; cruelty; insistent; insistence" },
	{ "question": "陶冶", "answers": [ "とうや" ], "comment": "training; education; cultivation" },
	{ "question": "陽炎", "answers": [ "かげろう" ], "comment": "heat haze; shimmer of hot air" },
	{ "question": "隘路", "answers": [ "あいろ" ], "comment": "defile; narrow path\nbottleneck; impasse" },
	{ "question": "雀斑", "answers": [ "そばかす" ], "comment": "freckles" },
	{ "question": "雄叫び", "answers": [ "おたけび" ], "comment": "war cry; roar" },
	{ "question": "雪隠", "answers": [ "せっちん" ], "comment": "toilet; lavatory" },
	{ "question": "雫", "answers": [ "しずく" ], "comment": "drop (of water); drip" },
	{ "question": "雲雀", "answers": [ "ひばり" ], "comment": "skylark (Alauda arvensis)\nMongolian lark (Melanocorypha mongolica)" },
	{ "question": "非道い", "answers": [ "ひどい" ], "comment": "cruel; heartless; hard; harsh; severe\nviolent; intense; strong; heavy; extreme\nvery bad; terrible; awful\nexcessive; exorbitant; unreasonable; outrageous; unfair; unjust" },
	{ "question": "面映ゆい", "answers": [ "おもはゆい" ], "comment": "embarrassed; self-conscious; bashful; abashed" },
	{ "question": "鞴", "answers": [ "ふいご" ], "comment": "(pair of) bellows" },
	{ "question": "頃日", "answers": [ "けいじつ" ], "comment": "recently; these days" },
	{ "question": "須く", "answers": [ "すべからく" ], "comment": "by all means; in all cases; ought to do" },
	{ "question": "頒布", "answers": [ "はんぷ" ], "comment": "distribution" },
	{ "question": "顰める", "answers": [ "しかめる", "ひそめる" ], "comment": "to pull a wry face; to screw one's face up; to pucker one's face; to scowl; to grimace; to frown\nto knit (one's eyebrows)" },
	{ "question": "顰蹙", "answers": [ "ひんしゅく" ], "comment": "frowning on; looking on with scorn; showing disapproval" },
	{ "question": "風靡", "answers": [ "ふうび" ], "comment": "overwhelming; conquering; dominating; sweeping (the world); swaying" },
	{ "question": "颯爽", "answers": [ "さっそう" ], "comment": "gallant; dashing; jaunty" },
	{ "question": "飛沫", "answers": [ "しぶき" ], "comment": "splash; spray\nsplash; spray" },
	{ "question": "食む", "answers": [ "はむ" ], "comment": "to eat (fodder, grass, etc.)\nto receive (a salary); to receive a stipend from one's lord" },
	{ "question": "餌食", "answers": [ "えじき" ], "comment": "prey; victim" },
	{ "question": "餞", "answers": [ "はなむけ" ], "comment": "farewell gift; parting gift; viaticum" },
	{ "question": "饒舌", "answers": [ "じょうぜつ" ], "comment": "garrulity; loquacity; talkativeness" },
	{ "question": "首肯く", "answers": [ "うなずく" ], "comment": "to nod; to bow one's head in assent; to agree" },
	{ "question": "馘首", "answers": [ "かくしゅ" ], "comment": "dismissal; discharge\nbeheading; decapitation" },
	{ "question": "馴致", "answers": [ "じゅんち" ], "comment": "taming; gradual habituation; leading to" },
	{ "question": "駱駝", "answers": [ "らくだ" ], "comment": "camel\ncamel (cloth); cloth made from camel hair\ncamel (color); light yellowish brown" },
	{ "question": "騙る", "answers": [ "かたる" ], "comment": "to swindle; to cheat; to take (something) away by deception\nto misrepresent oneself (as); to lie (e.g. about one's name or status); to falsify (e.g. a seal); to assume (a name); to pretend (to be)" },
	{ "question": "驕る", "answers": [ "おごる" ], "comment": "to give (someone) a treat\nto be extravagant; to live luxuriously\nto be proud; to be haughty" },
	{ "question": "髑髏", "answers": [ "どくろ" ], "comment": "skull (esp. weatherbeaten, used as symbol of death); death's head; cranium" },
	{ "question": "鯱", "answers": [ "しゃち" ], "comment": "orca (Orcinus orca); killer whale; grampus\nmythical carp with the head of a lion and the body of a fish (auspicious protectors of well-being)\nmythical carp with the head of a lion and the body of a fish (auspicious protectors of well-being)" },
	{ "question": "鰈", "answers": [ "かれい" ], "comment": "righteye flounder (any fish of family Pleuronectidae)" },
	{ "question": "鶴嘴", "answers": [ "つるはし" ], "comment": "pickaxe" },
	{ "question": "麾下", "answers": [ "きか" ], "comment": "under the command (of); under the banner (of); influenced (by)" },
	{ "question": "黴", "answers": [ "かび" ], "comment": "mold; mould; mildew" },
	{ "question": "黴菌", "answers": [ "ばいきん" ], "comment": "germ; germs; bacteria; mold; mould\nsomething harmful; vermin" },
	{ "question": "鼈", "answers": [ "すっぽん" ], "comment": "Chinese soft-shelled turtle (Pelodiscus sinensis); soft-shelled turtle (Trionychidae)" },
	{ "question": "齟齬", "answers": [ "そご" ], "comment": "inconsistency; discord; conflict; discrepancy; contradiction; failure; frustration" },
	{ "question": "齧る", "answers": [ "かじる" ], "comment": "to gnaw; to nibble; to bite; to munch; to crunch\nto dabble in; to have a smattering of" }
]
}
